originenergy.com.au 2015-03-23

# Privacy - Origin Energy

We are committed to protecting your privacy and to appropriately managing the personal and credit related information that we hold about you in accordance with the requirements of the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth). 

## Privacy Policy

We will collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information. 

More information about how to access and correct the credit related information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your credit related information (and how we will deal with it) can be found in our Credit Reporting Policy, which forms part of our Privacy Policy. 

Read our Privacy Policy

Download our Privacy Policy 

A combined copy of Origin’s Privacy Collection Statement for Customers and Credit Reporting Collection Statement in printable format can be accessed below. 

Download a printable copy 

## 1\. Privacy Collection Statement for Customers & Prospective Customers

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) or one of its Australian subsidiaries (together, **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au). 

We collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information (which includes your name, address, telephone and other contact details and banking and credit card details) in order to provide you with energy and related products and services and to process your payments for these products and services.

We may also: 

  * collect sensitive information about you in some circumstances (for example, if life support equipment is used at your supply address);
  * collect, use, hold and disclose additional confidential information that is not personal information (which may include metering data and other information where required under applicable laws) for these purposes; 
  * if you request that we provide a quote for our products and services, use your personal information to provide that quote, including to follow up if we do not hear from you; 
  * collect personal information about you from third parties, but will take reasonable steps to ensure that you are aware of the matters contained in this privacy collection statement; 
  * disclose your personal information to our related parties, contractors, agents, other energy distributors or retailers, government bodies and regulatory authorities (where required or authorised by law) and our service providers; and 
  * use your personal information for marketing purposes, including disclosing it to third parties who undertake marketing activities on our behalf, and may present you with gas, electricity, green products and other household or business service offers in the future (including after your agreement with us ends). 

If you choose not to provide your personal information to us, we may not be able to answer your query or provide energy and related products and services to you. 

We may hold personal information about you in, or may disclose this information to third party service providers located in one or more overseas countries. Your personal information may be held in New Zealand, the United States of America, India, the Philippines, Singapore, Vietnam, Chile, Botswana, Indonesia and Papua New Guinea. If your personal information is held in other overseas countries in the future we will update this collection statement. 

We may also collect, use, hold and disclose certain credit related information about you. We may collect such credit related information from, and disclose credit related information to, credit reporting bodies and other entities that provide credit directly to you. For more information, please see our specific Credit Reporting Collection Statement.

We will otherwise collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information. Our credit reporting policy, which forms part of our general Privacy Policy, sets out how we will collect, hold, use and disclose any credit related information about you, how you may access and correct the credit related information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your credit related information.

## 2\. Privacy Collection Statement for Landholders

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) or one of its Australian subsidiaries (together, **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact, but you can also call us on 1800 526 369 or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au)

We collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information (which includes your name, address, telephone, other contact details and banking details) in order to manage our relationship with you or your relationship with third parties that we act or perform functions for. If it is relevant to the business relationship, we may also collect sensitive information. We may collect personal information about you from third parties, but will take reasonable steps to ensure that you been made aware of the matters contained in this privacy collection statement. If you choose not to provide your personal information to us, we may not be able to answer your query or have a business or other relationship with you. 

We may disclose your personal information to third parties, which may include our joint venture partners, entities that we act or provide functions for, our services providers, your authorised representative(s) and government and regulatory authorities (where required or authorised by law). These third parties will manage your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies and we ask that these third parties hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act.

We will otherwise collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information.

## 3\. Privacy Collection Statement for Community Engagement & Stakeholders

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) or one of its Australian subsidiaries (together, **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au).

When we interact with community organisations and similar stakeholders, we may collect personal information about identified individuals or the representatives of these organisations as part of this engagement process. We may collect your name, address and contact details, as well as any other personal information necessary to respond to enquiries or to address any community or other concerns that have been raised with us or in relation to third parties that we act or perform functions for. If it is relevant to the enquiry or concern, this may include collecting sensitive information.

We only collect, use, hold and disclose personal information to the extent necessary to engage with community organisations and similar stakeholders. If you choose not to provide your personal information to us, we may not be able to answer your query, provide any information or otherwise effectively address any community or other concerns that have been raised with us. 

We may disclose your personal information to third parties, which may include our joint venture partners, entities that we act or provide functions for, our services providers, your authorised representative(s) and government and regulatory authorities (where required or authorised by law).

These third parties will manage your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies and we ask that these third parties hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act.

We will otherwise collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information.

## 4\. Privacy Collection Statement for Shareholders

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) ( **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au). 

We collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information (which includes your name, address, telephone and other contact details, date of birth, tax file number and banking details) in connection with your shareholding, to keep our share registry up to date and to pay any dividends to you. The collection of this information may be required under the _Corporations Act 2001_ (Cth) or the _Anti-Money Laundering and Counter Terrorism Financing Act 2006_ (Cth). If you do not provide your personal information to us, you may not be able to become a shareholder.

We may disclose your personal information to our share registry operator, contractors, agents, government bodies and regulators and to our service providers and professional advisors. In certain circumstances, we may be required by law to grant access to anyone who wishes to inspect our share register and to provide a copy to them.

We will otherwise collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information.

## 5\. Privacy Collection Statement for Other Contractors & Visitors

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) or one of its Australian subsidiaries (together, **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au). 

We collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information (which includes your name, address, contact details and details of your employer) in connection with allowing you to access any sites, offices, buildings or other premises that we own or lease or which are under our control. We may also collect sensitive information, including health information, about you in some circumstances (such as if one of our representatives requests that you submit to a drug or alcohol test while on our premises). If you do not provide your personal information to us (including consenting to our collection of your sensitive information), you may not be allowed to access our premises or you may be asked to leave our premises. 

We may disclose your personal information to our contractors, agents, government bodies, local authorities and to our service providers. 

We will otherwise collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information. 

## 6\. Privacy Collection Statement for General Enquiries

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) or one of its Australian subsidiaries (together, **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au).

We collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information (which includes your name, address, telephone and other contact details) in order to answer your query or provide you with a report, document or other information that you have requested. If you choose not to provide your personal information to us, we may not be able to answer your query or provide the report, document or other information that you have requested.

We may disclose your personal information to our contractors, agents, government bodies, local authorities and to our service providers. 

We will otherwise collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which sets out how you may access and correct the personal information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your personal information.

## 7\. Credit Reporting Collection Statement

Your information is being collected by Origin Energy Limited (ABN 30 000 051 696) or one of its Australian subsidiaries (together, **we** or **us** ). Our contact details are available at originenergy.com.au/contact or you can email us at: [privacy@originenergy.com.au](mailto:privacy@originenergy.com.au).

We may collect, use, hold and disclose certain credit related information about you for the purposes of providing you with energy and related products and services and to process your payments for these products and services. Credit related information includes information such as your name and contact details, your credit history (including any repayments or late repayments you have made), details of any credit you have sought or obtained from other credit providers, any credit rating or credit assessment score that we calculate or that a credit reporting body might provide to us and details of any credit-related court proceedings or insolvency applications that relate to you.

We may collect credit related information about you from credit reporting bodies and other credit providers who have provided credit to you. We may use and hold this credit related information in order to conduct a credit assessment on you, to evaluate your credit-worthiness and to decide whether to provide you with energy and related products and services on credit. We may disclose your credit related information and your personal information third parties, including debt collectors, credit management agencies, other credit providers, credit reporting bodies and government bodies and regulatory authorities (where required or authorised by law). Credit reporting bodies collect a range of credit related information about individuals and use that information to provide a credit-related service to their customers (which include us). The credit reporting bodies that we may disclose your information to are: 

  * Dun & Bradstreet (Australia) Pty Ltd (contact details available at [www.checkyourcredit.com.au/ContactUs ](http://www.checkyourcredit.com.au/ContactUs)); and 
  *   * Veda Advantage Information Services and Solutions Limited (contact details are available at [www.mycreditfile.com.au/support ](http://www.mycreditfile.com.au/support)). 

If we disclose your information to other credit reporting bodies in the future we will update this collection statement. 

These credit reporting bodies may include your information in reports provided to other credit providers to assist them to assess your credit worthiness. If you do not pay for the energy and related products and services that we provide to you, if you commit fraud or try to do so, or if you otherwise commit a serious credit infringement, we may disclose this information to these credit reporting bodies. This may affect your ability to obtain credit in the future. 

We also have a credit reporting policy, which forms part of our general Privacy Policy. You may obtain a copy of the credit reporting bodies’ credit reporting policies by contacting them using the contact details set out above. 

You have a right to access the credit related information that we hold about you, to correct that credit related information and to make a complaint about our handling of your credit related information. More information about how to access and correct the credit related information that we hold about you and how to lodge a complaint relating to our treatment of your credit related information (and how we will deal with it) can be found in our credit reporting policy.

You also have a right to request that credit reporting bodies do not use any credit related information held by them for the purposes of pre-screening any direct marketing by credit providers. If you would like to make such a request, please contact the credit reporting bodies using the contact details set out above. 

We disclose credit related information to third parties that provide services to us or that provide services to you on our behalf. We may hold this credit related information in, or may disclose this information to third party services providers located in, one or more overseas countries. Your credit related information may be held in New Zealand, the United States of America, India, the Philippines, Singapore, Vietnam, Chile, Botswana, Indonesia and Papua New Guinea. If your credit related information is held in other overseas countries in the future we will update this collection statement.

If you believe that you have been a victim of fraud or identity theft, you have a right to contact the credit reporting bodies and ask them not to disclose your credit related information. If you would like to make such a request, please contact the credit reporting bodies using the contact details set out above.
